Hello friends, today we will talk
about insurance, see insurance is
very important, Akhilesh, students,
what is it, and get the insurance done,
in actual, if suppose you are doing
morning right now, by the way,
someone does not agree with you, then
after you leave, how will your family members
serve you, there is insurance for that,
but those who are urgent, they
fool us so much in the center that they
change the meaning of extra oil inference for their own benefit,
so today we will know which
insurance we should actually get
and which one we should not get, there are
three types of insurance and
in pairs, it is told by urgent,
one is endowment plan, second is
term life insurance and one is
health insurance,
understand everything like Ambani, what is the difference between the three, in these there is
dormant plan, in that we have to pay
a premium tax, which
after death we get its refund,
and in term life insurance,
you only have to pay, you do
not get anything else  You
understand that when you fall ill in health insurance, then
you get the benefit only after getting treatment.
Now let us understand its difference better. What
happens in endowment plan is
that the life insurance that you get is very less,
like if you are
paying a premium of Rs.30000, then you
get a maximum premium of Rs.5 lakh or Rs.10 lakh
because you will get it after I die or
if it does not settle with you, then that
diamond which your family gets.
In religious life insurance, you have to pay a lesser amount and you will get
nothing, but if
by mistake it does not settle with you, then
you get a huge amount, like
in this you will have to pay Rs.3000 or Rs.4500 per year
and easily a premium of up to Rs.1 crore will be given to
your family and that amount will be given to you. That is why full life
insurance is better. See friends, we get it done so that
after our death,
our family can get some support, so
see what happens in investment plan.  It
happens that they get a
commission of up to 20 percent and in the term
life insurance there is only two to
three percent, that is why they will never
tell you to get life insurance,
they will always focus on endowment plan, so for
your own good you should get a term
life insurance, it is
better to get an FD than this
because there is a benefit of pinch run in it
but it is very less, there is very less coverage in it, there is
no benefit from it, it is better if you
want to get a guaranteed endowment plan then get a
better FD than this and I would say
that you should always get term life insurance
which is much better, it has a lot of
coverage, if your mother gets a
mishap, now you might be
earning even one lakh rupees in seven months, then easily, if you
give six to seven thousand or 10,000 then you will have two crores,
which will be the amount on the Nuve,
after your mishap if your family gets 2 crores, then they will
also deposit it in the bank, so that their health gets better easily  You will
spend your entire life and
see anything, never do an endowment plan,
get a time license currency, now let's talk about
health insurance, this is also very important
because you have worked hard all your life and
earned all the money and when you go to the hospital, at the
most
if you earn Rs 10 lakh profit in 1 to 2 months then Rs 10 lakh will be very
less for your one hospital visit,
so health insurance is also very
important, get it approved also,
but keep in mind that in dormant
plan not loose, instead of taking an endowment plan, it is
better to get it tested and if you want to take it, then
take term life insurance and obviously do
not be greedy that if you give something then you should get something in return,
you get insurance done so that
after your face there should be some support for your family, so
take special care of this thing and get term life insurance
only, so thank you, if the information is good, do
subscribe and